# Resume: Er Galvão Abbott

https://galvao.eti.br

Professional with more than 25 years of experience in developing web applications, being more than 20 of these with the PHP language and more than 12 with Zend Framework / Laminas Project. Highly present in the Brazilian Software Community, being the Director of PHP Conference Brasil and Con-FLOSS and being a speaker in national and international events. Guest Post-Graduation Professor (Specialist) at UNOESC (SC), Faculdade Alfa (PR) and Unicesumar (PR). Fedora Ambassador- LATAM, the first Brazilian to become Postman Supernova, Evangelist and contributor to the PHP language and for Laminas Project. Security, Quality and Open Source Enthusiast.

# Professional Experience

# Vox Tecnologia

Senior Programmer II - 04/04/2022 - 08/10/2022

- Adapta Oracle SQL queries for PostgreSQL;
- Development for the company's softwares;
- Legacy Code Optimization

## **UOL EdTech**

Project Manager - 05/03/2021 - 03/18/2022

- Developing a CLI application for data anonimization in order for the company to be compliant with LGPD (Brazilian counterpart to GDPR);
- Design of a new architeture proposal for the company's systems, with frequent conversations and eventual approval of all Tech Leaders;
- Support to Developers and DevOps in questions about the language;
- Legacy Code Optimization.

#### Vivaweb

Senior Programmer - 07/08/2020 - 04/09/2021

- Web development for the company's flagship product;
- Analysis and Specification of an API based on the OpenAPI Specification;
- Developing a browser extension for the company's webchat.

#### Several

**Developer, Instructor and Freelance Consultant - 2011 - 2020** • Web application development for several companies;

- Consulting in AppSec, performing semi-automated penetration tests, result analysis and report composition for clients in my home state and Sao Paulo;
- In-company training for companies all over Brasil, including: Banco da Amazônia (PA), USP (SP), Public Data Processing centers for the governments of Minas Gerais and Santa Catarina, among others.

## Dinamize

**Programmer - 01/19/2011 - 07/22/2011 •** Web development for the company's e-mail marketing management product.

## LNX Open

Freelance Programmer - 07/01/2010 - 11/05/2010 • Web development for PROCERGS (Data Processing Government Agency in Rio Grande do Sul), working on several government portals such as IRGA, DETRAN, SETUR Porto Alegre, among others.

## HD Interactive, Inc.

Freelance Programmer - 12/06/2009 - 07/13/2010 • Reorganizing the company's developing routines, suggesting the adoption of technologies and policies to improve the application development process;

• Programming several projects for the company's clients.

#### Alert Logic, Inc.

Freelance Programmer - 03/15/2007 - 11/29/2007 • Developing the web interface for Invision, an Intrusion Detection Software, involving report generating scripts, user prefernces customization, PDF generation, with JavaScript, PHP and MySQL;

• Conceptualizing and implementing - alongside a colleague - of a way to validate data from HTML forms that can be used either on backend or frontend, using JavaScript, XML and PHP.

## CCA

Freelance Programmer - 10/19/2005 - 01/19/2006 • PHP development for a system that manages data for Rio Grande do Sul's City Halls.

#### Informa Brasil

**Programmer - 05/24/2002 - 09/17/2003** • Conversion, through analysis of concepts and inner workings, of a web based system developen with ASP/MS SQL Server to PHP/Oracle/PostgreSQL;

• Web development for the company's flagship product, including an automatic parsing routine for texts, using relationships with two relational databases adding up to millions of records.

#### Meta Serviços em Informática

Freelance Programmer - 04/19/2000 - 04/29/2002 • Dvelopment of an Iternal Requests Managing System for Telefónica, one of the company's most prominent clients. Development used Perl with an Oracle database.

# Voyager Internet

Web Developer - 06/01/1997 - 12/14/1999 • Developing and maintaining the ISP's Portal, including highlight features, such as downloads portal, webmail, webchat, etc...

## Education

# College (Incomplete):

Social Communication - Advertising

Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul (PUC-RS)

# **High School**

Curso Supletivo Pré-Universitário ### Grand and Middle School IMEC - Instituto Metodista de Educação e Cultura - Colégio Americano

# Skills

# Languages:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON, OAS, XML, Perl, PHP, SQL ### Frameworks: CodeIgniter, Laravel, Laminas MVC, Laminas Mezzio ### RDBMs: MariaDB/MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle ### OSs: Linux (Fedora, Ubuntu, Debian)